A man: Allahu Akbar. Allahu Akbar.
Ash-hadu Alla Elaha Ella Allah
Hayya Alal Salat. Hayya Alal Salat
Hayya Alal Falah. Hayya Alal Falah
Allahu Akbar. Allahu Akbar.
A man: La Elaha Ella Allah
Dr. Khalifa: Alhamdu Lillah, Wa Ash-hadu Alla Elaha Ella Allah Wahdahu La Shareeka Lah.
This first Khutba will link up with the Khutbas that Dean Majul has been giving us.
And before I start, I would like to draw your attention to something that we probably take for granted,
and that is, here is a mosque that advocates the worship of Allah alone.
I know that God sent Moses to preach La Elaha Ella Allah, as we know in Sura 21,
and not to preach the glorification of Moses.
And God sent Jesus to preach the worship of God alone, La Elaha Ella Allah,
and not to preach the glorification of Jesus.
And God sent Muhammad to preach the worship of God alone,
and not to preach the glorification of Muhammad or anyone else.
Just worshiping God alone.
In this mosque, we advocate the worship of God alone, and we follow the Quran to the letter.
We came to call this mosque the University of God, because it is the most important education,
and we have been very fortunate in seeing the truth of the Quran and sticking to every letter of it.
The University of God, the most important education,
lacked official professorship.
So, you can see from God's vantage point, He said, well, these people are advocating the worship of Me alone, God alone,
and they need a professor.
So, let's send them a professor.
So, God appoints a couple of angels to go and hunt for the best professor on earth.
And He gets us not only a professor, but a Dean of the Islamic Institute in the Philippines.
Dr. Khalifa: Now, he doesn't know why he is here in Tucson.
Dean Majul: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: All he knows is, he sit down in Tucson, he got stuck to the Masjid Tucson.
And he's teaching us, bless his heart, and he's been teaching us about Adam and Eve and the sin of Adam and Eve.
And we've been enjoying his teachings, so we have an official,
not just any professor, the Dean himself,
of an official school, so we, we don't lack officialdom in here.
What Dean Majul has been teaching us, the last few Khutbas of his, were the sin of Adam and Eve.
What was the sin of Adam and Eve?
They ate from the tree.
That's what they did.
And because they ate from the tree, they did not qualify to continue in Jannah, in Heaven, in Paradise,
the Kingdom of God.
Because they ate from the tree.
They committed one sin.
What does this teach us? What do we learn from this important lesson?
We learn that you cannot go to Jannah with one sin.
If you have one sin in your record, you do not qualify to go to Heaven.
Sounds difficult.
But for the people who worship Allah alone, it is not difficult at all.
Because there are two ways of wiping out the sins from your record.
And this means, nobody will see them, you will not see them in the record,
if you fulfill these two requirements.
But the thing we must learn, from Dean Majul's lessons in the past,
that Adam's and Eve's sin is, they ate from the tree, they were kicked out.
Because they committed one sin.
Therefore, we learn from this, that we cannot go to Heaven with one sin on our record. Not one.
If you commit one sin, and you have it in your record, then you will die,
you cannot go to Heaven.
You must be absolutely sinless.
Because when Adam and Eve ate from the tree, they didn't commit murder.
You know, they ate from the tree.
That's all they did.
God told them, you go on Heaven, and eat from anything you want, but not this one tree.
They ate from the tree, and they were kicked out.
And this is exactly what we're doing here on this earth.
We are here to be tested, and to end this life without a single sin in your record.
Otherwise, you do not qualify to join the Kingdom of God,
you do not qualify to enter Jannah.
Now, how do we, what are the ways of erasing sin from your record?
Now, this is one thing you must remember.
You must, must never forget that our goal is to end this life without a single sin.
How can we do that?
The first method of erasing sin is Tawbah, repentance.
That's one thing.
You turn to God and you say, I'm sorry, I made a mistake, I will never do it again.
I pledge, I will never do it again, I repent, I'm sorry, I apologize.
All the words of apology that you can muster.
And you pledge solemnly that you will not do it again.
That's one way.
What if your repentance is not acceptable?
There comes the second way. The second way is to pay for it.
The first way to erase sins is, is Tawbah, repentance.
And the second way is to pay for them here in this world.
And they are very expensive, I'm telling you.
I would like to, to put a, a dollar value on the sins and how you pay for them here in this world.
Now, as a believer, you will pay in material things.
Thank God, you do not pay with your arm or your leg or...
Just look around this mosque, you don't see anyone with one arm or one leg, Alhamdu Lillah.
You have to say Alhamdu Lillah every time.
But, you will, when I put material values in it, it seems like the punishment is out of proportion for the sin.
But you have to pay for it, if, unless you wanna, you want it in your record.
Dr. Khalifa: If you want one, if you have one sin on your record, you cannot go to Jannah.
A woman: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: People go and commit adultery, and they think it's a simple matter.
Well, marriage is really a simple matter.
If you have a relationship with another person, you might as well want to suggest marriage.
It's very simple, two witnesses, you call Allah, you declare that you're married.
But if you fall into adultery,
Dr. Khalifa: my dollar value on it is ten thousand dollars.
A woman: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: You have to pay
in misery, or if you don't have the ten thousand dollars, it will be in problems.
The payment for sins seems to be out of proportion in this world, but really it isn't.
It's a tremendous mercy.
So, the believers are the only people who enjoy certain problems in this world,
because they know they are paying for certain, wiping out certain sins.
The believer does not get away with sins in this world, he has to pay for it.
The disbeliever doesn't either, except with the disbeliever, the punishment continues in the Hereafter.
With the disbeliever, the punishment in this world, it also comes in this world, but he or she cannot make the connection.
They will appear to get away with sin.
And then, after years, months, after a time when the person cannot connect
the punishment with the sin, bang!
They get hit.
So, the two ways to erase sins are repentance and paying for them.
These are the only two ways.
There's one sin, not sin, it's not even a sin, there's one offense that cannot be forgiven.
The only unforgivable offense, I will let you open the Qurans, now read from your Qurans,
and get Sura 39, verse 53.
No, excuse me, I made a mistake, 4:48.
Dr. Khalifa: Not even that, 4:17.
A woman: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: (unintelligible)
A man: What Sura?
Dr. Khalifa: 4:17 is page 53.
Alright, this is the order God wants us to see.
This is not the one that I wanted to do, but it deals with repentance.
Page 53, verse 16 says,
[4:17]  Repentance is accepted by GOD from those who fall in sin due to ignorance, then repent immediately. GOD redeems these. And GOD is Knower, Wise.
So, this is how repentance, repentance is accepted.
Let's go on.
[4:18]  But repentance is not acceptable from those who continue to commit sins until death comes to them, then say, "Now I repent." Nor is it acceptable from those who die as disbelievers. We have prepared for these a painful retribution.
So, repentance, there are conditions for accepting Tawbah, for accepting repentance.
That you fall in sin due to ignorance.
In other words, you don't know that wine is Haram,
and you go drink wine.
Then, you find out in Quran that wine, liquor, alcohol is Haram.
Then, you repent.
And you pledge you'll never do it again.
You made a mistake, you'll never do it again.
Then, you repent and it's accepted.
But if you know that wine, liquor, whiskey, marijuana, or any of those is Haram,
and you go deliberately and you do it, you cannot repent from that.
You have to pay.
And the price is very high,
either here, or there.
If you know that adultery is Haram, and you go commit it,
you cannot repent from that.
There is no repentance there. You have to pay.
And the pay is very expensive, ten thousand dollars.
You know, the prostitutes are down there for fifty dollars or a hundred or something.
But the price that you pay, according to God's law
is, I put a figure on it, just roughly, ten thousand dollars.
In misery, or problems, or whatever.
So, this is the condition for repentance.
You can repent only if you fall into sin due to ignorance, and then repent immediately.
You can't linger.
In the right way, you say, I'm sorry God, I made a mistake.
That's, that's, these are the conditions for repentance.
Also, let's go to 39:65.
Because when I say you cannot go to Heaven with one sin,
it sounds terrible, doesn't it?
Not one sin.
Because Adam and Eve ate from the tree, just committed one sin.
39:65.
Dr. Khalifa: Sura Al-Zumer
A man: What's the page?
Dr. Khalifa: 319. Page 319, verse number 65.
No, that's not the one.
53.
Excuse me, it's on the same page anyway.
It says,
[39:53]  Say to My servants who exceeded the limits, never despair of God's mercy. GOD forgives all sins. For He is the Forgiver, the Merciful."
Now, the Arabic is even a lot stronger.
قُلْ يَعِبَادِىَ ٱلَّذِينَ أَسْرَفُوا عَلَىٓ أَنفُسِهِمْ لَا تَقْنَطُوا مِن رَّحْمَةِ ٱللَّهِ إِنَّ ٱللَّهَ يَغْفِرُ ٱلذُّنُوبَ جَمِيعًا (39:53)
All sins. God forgives all sins.
Moses committed murder.
But he was forgiven.
If you remember the Quran, Moses immediately turned to God and said, this is the act of the devil, please God forgive me.
He repented immediately, didn't he?
And he didn't intend to kill the man either.
But he was forgiven right there in the same prayer.
The same verse of the Quran.
So, God forgives all sins.
The instruction here for us is never to despair from God's mercy.
There is one unforgivable offense.
Now, that's the one in 4:48.
Let's go to 4:48.
Down at the bottom of the page, it says,
Idol worship, the only unforgivable offense.
[4:48] GOD never forgives the idolization of anything besides Him,* and He forgives all lesser offenses for whomever He wills. Anyone who sets up any idol besides GOD, has forged a gross blasphemy.
Therefore, the only unforgivable offense is idol worship.
And this is why we are very careful in this mosque not to idolize anyone,
not Mary, not Jesus, not Muhammad, not Moses, not any, not any saint, not anyone, not anything.
Our motto is Allah alone.
And the criterion is in the Quran.
that
إِذَا ذُكِرَ ٱللَّهُ وَحْدَهُ ٱشْمَأَزَّتْ قُلُوبُ ٱلَّذِينَ لَا يُؤْمِنُونَ بِٱلْـَٔاخِرَةِ (39:45)
When you talk about God alone, they don't like it.
That's the sign, but we love it.
We talk about Allah alone.
Because idol worship is the only unforgivable offense.
That's a goal in the same,
in the same Sura, verse 116, 116.
It is page 63.
Again at the bottom of the page, it says,
[4:116] GOD does not forgive the idolization of any idols besides Him (if maintained until death),* and He forgives all lesser offenses for whomever He wills. Anyone who idolizes any idol besides GOD has gone far astray.
So, now we know that there is only one
unforgivable offense, and that is idol worship,
to idolize anyone or anything.
Just the one that is not forgivable.
Because the whole idea of creating us in this world
is to worship Allah alone.
And this is why we are told throughout Quran
that the prophets have no power to benefit you or harm you,
have no power to benefit themselves or harm themselves.
Why is God saying that?
Why?
Because the people have tendency to idolize their leaders,
their saints, their prophets.
Christians idolize Jesus, the Muslims idolize Muhammad.
The Shia idolize the Imams.
It's a plague.
It's a plague that, that Satan set up
for the Jews, the Christians and the Muslims.
And people fall in it.
And we find it reflected in the Quran, a statement of fact.
(12:106) وَمَا يُؤْمِنُ أَكْثَرُهُم بِٱللَّهِ إِلَّا وَهُم مُّشْرِكُونَ
The majority of believers fall in idol worship.
(12:103) وَمَآ أَكْثَرُ ٱلنَّاسِ وَلَوْ حَرَصْتَ بِمُؤْمِنِينَ
The majority of people will not believe to start with,
and the majority of the minority will fall in idol worship.
This is why you must be absolutely positive and careful that you are idolizing no one,
that you are worshiping Allah alone,
that you are following the Quran alone,
the words of Allah alone.
You don't accept any instructions from anyone because God is the Wisest.
So with this in mind, we know that all sins are forgivable.
The only unforgivable offense is idol worship.
And we know that we cannot go to Heaven with one sin.
We must erase all sins.
When we die, we mustn't have one sin in our record.
Otherwise, you don't go to Heaven.
We are here in this world to prepare for entering Heaven.
That's what we want, the real life, the eternal life.
Because this life is zero.
So in order to qualify, you have to erase all the sins.
You can erase by Tawbah, repentance, and by paying for them.
Therefore, I, I propose that we go out of these doors absolutely sinless.
We're gonna walk out of these doors without a single sin in our record.
Because we're going to repent right now.
We're going to turn to God and we're gonna declare Tawbah.
We're gonna pledge that we will never break God's law,
that we will follow His commandments as stated here,
and that we'll never offend God in any way.
Idol worship is out of the question.
We did that long time ago.
But we're going to turn to God and sincerely pledge,
we're gonna repent of all the past sins and offenses.
We're gonna say that we'. e sorry that we fell into those mistakes.
We'll apologize and we will pledge, this is most important, that we will never again commit a sin.
You have to mean it.
You may fall in sin again, which you will,
but God says in the Quran that He loves
(2:222) إِنَّ ٱللَّهَ يُحِبُّ ٱلتَّوَّبِينَ
those who continuously repent.
He didn't say,
إِنَّ ٱللَّهَ يُحِبُّ تَائِبِينَ
He said,
تَّوَّبِينَ
because you continuously repent.
You have to repent every day.
But as far as we're concerned at this moment,
we're gonna walk out of these doors absolutely sinless.
So, turn to God and repent.
Tooboo Ela Allah
Alhamdu Lillah, Wa Ash-hadu Alla Elaha Ella Allah Wahdahu La Shareeka Lah.
When you repent, you wipe out all the sins in your record,
and you qualify to go to Heaven.
If you die right now at this moment, you go to Heaven straight,
because you're not gonna have a sin in your record.
And remember the conditions for repentance.
In the future, when you reach for a cup of whiskey or wine,
or something, you know it is wrong,
and you know you're gonna pay for it dearly.
It's very expensive.
I remember one time, I was in Libya at the time, and,
and I was buying donuts from this fellow,
and he had a bottle of whiskey next to him.
He was a cashier,
and he was drinking away, and I said,
you know, this is very expensive.
He said, "yeah, I paid 8 pounds for this."
I said, I said, no, that's not what I mean.
Cause it's gonna cost you a lot.
So, it's very expensive, you're breaking God's law.
As far as Adam and Eve is concerned,
it cost them Heaven.
Heaven is a carte blanche,
you do anything you want.
God says, you get anything you wish, and I have more.
I have more than you wish.
Because God has things that we cannot even imagine,
in order to wish.
You know, how can you wish for something you cannot imagine?
Pleasures and joy that you cannot imagine.
God says,
(50:35) وَلَدَيْنَا مَزِيدٌ
And I have more than what you wish for.
And now that you're sinless, try to maintain this condition.
If you're about to commit a sin,
be prepared to pay for it, dearly,
expensively.
You know, what is worse with sins
is if they really, if they really become too much,
then they, there's, there's a shield that builds up with every sin,
and if there's too much of that around you,
people cannot penetrate that shield.
But never despair from God's mercy.
You must repent immediately,
whether you know it or not.
If you fall in sin, knowingly or unknowingly,
repent anyway, immediately.
And be prepared for the price.
And you pay the price happily.
Anytime God says, you shall not,
you shall not,
no matter how simple it seems.
The second Khutba is about the importance of the Arabic language.
This is the second Khutba.
Because we started the Arabic language lessons recently.
And I'm gonna summarize the whole Khutba in one word.
Let me make it two words.
Not important at all.
That's four words.
Arabic is not important at all.
Because we learn from Sura 41,
let's look at it, 41:44.
You, most of you are familiar with this.
41:44 is in page 332.
It says,
[41:44]  Had we made it a non-Arabic Quran they would have said, "Why did it come down in that language?" Whether it is non-Arabic or Arabic, say, "For those who believe, it is a beacon and a healing regardless of their language. As for those who do not believe, they will be deaf and blind to it, as if they are being called from afar."
So, language is absolutely immaterial.
If you're a believer,
you're a sincere Muslim,
then God will put everything in your heart,
the whole Quran in your heart.
I've seen people quote the Quran without ever reading it, because they're sincere Muslims.
They haven't read it all yet,
they're working on it.
At the same time, if you're a professor of Arabic linguistics
at the Mecca University or whatever,
and you are not a sincere believer,
you cannot get one Arabic word from the Quran,
even though you're a professor of Arabic language.
Because this is what God says,
[41:44]  ... As for those who do not believe, they will be ... blind to it, ...
They cannot get one word out of this.
At the same time, a Japanese, a French, a Swede,
or one who does not know one letter in the Arabic language,
God will put the Quran in his heart.
Otherwise, it will not be fair.
Because the Quran is for the whole world,
for everybody,
and it will not be fair
to restrict it to those who can read and write Arabic.
As you see from this verse,
the title of the Sura is Fussilat, elucidated.
God made the Quran available to every believer.
And also, the Quran is very special. The Quran is never available
to those who are not believers,
people who do not believe the Quran.
But the Arabic, the Arabic helps.
Just like mathematics or physics or chemistry,
it helps.
And this is why we have the Arabic lessons.
I'm gonna give you one example where the Arabic helps.
I wrote it out there.
Because the, the Muslim Ummah
is trapped in the, in a, in a satanic lot
where they cannot,
they do not believe God
when He says that the Quran is complete and perfect.
They have to go to other sources.
They have five sources of Sharia.
They have the Quran, the Hadith, the 'Ijma' (unanimity),
Qiyas,
that is analogy,
and all kinds of other sources.
And God says,
if you go to any other source besides Quran,
you are setting up a god beside God.
I'm gonna read the verse for you. It happens to be verse 19 in Sura 6.
قُلْ أَىُّ شَىْءٍ أَكْبَرُ شَهَدَةً قُلِ ٱللَّهُ شَهِيدٌ بَيْنِى وَبَيْنَكُمْ وَأُوحِىَ إِلَىَّ هَذَا ٱلْقُرْءَانُ لِأُنذِرَكُم بِهِ وَمَن بَلَغَ أَئِنَّكُمْ لَتَشْهَدُونَ أَنَّ مَعَ ٱللَّهِ ءَالِهَةً أُخْرَى قُل لَّآ أَشْهَدُ (6:19)
So, the people set up other sources besides Quran,
other gods beside God,
against the will of God and the will of the prophet.
And they think that they are guided.
One perfect example of the Arabic language is this verse here.
It says, it's, it's Sura 17 verse 45. It says,
[17:45]  When you read the Quran, we place between you and those who do not believe in the Hereafter an invisible barrier.
[17:46]  And we put shields on their hearts, to prevent them from understanding Quran, and deafness in their ears. And when you preach your Lord, in the Quran alone,* ...
God put the world alone after Quran.
They turn away, they run.
They don't like it. They run.
And we have seen this. We have seen people who will come here
and you tell them the Quran alone,
and they run.
They can't stand it.
Just like the Quran says,
(17:46) وَلَّوْا عَلَىٓ أَدْبَرِهِمْ نُفُورًا
Now, because of the general trap that the Muslim Ummah fell in,
they refuse to translate this the way it is.
They say, if you preach your Lord alone in the Quran,...
You just pick up any translation of the Quran.
And you will find that they, they move the word Wahdahu (وَحْدَهُ)
after your Lord.
And this is why in, in our translation, we put Wahdahu (وَحْدَهُ)
after your Lord and after the Quran
because God put it after the Quran in Arabic.
This sentence would have been perfectly,
perfectly perfect if you say,
وَإِذَا ذَكَرْتَ رَبَّكَ وَحْدَهُ فِى ٱلْقُرْءَانِ وَلَّوْا عَلَىٓ أَدْبَرِهِمْ نُفُورًا
But God deliberately put the word Wahdahu (وَحْدَهُ)
after Al-Quran (ٱلْقُرْءَانِ).
So, if you know Arabic,
it will help you distinguish and understand
that the majority of people are plagued with idol worship.
(12:106) وَمَا يُؤْمِنُ أَكْثَرُهُم بِٱللَّهِ إِلَّا وَهُم مُّشْرِكُونَ
And they are, they are plagued to the extent
that they refuse to believe the Quran.
They refuse to translate the truth of the Quran.
They cannot stand when you say Quran alone.
God is not enough for them.
They have to have Hadith and Sunnah and, and Qiyas and 'Ijma' and all these other sources
that were invented centuries after the prophet,
including the Hadith and Sunnah.
So, this is an example of the importance of the Arabic language.
And while here the expression
(17:45) ٱلَّذِينَ لَا يُؤْمِنُونَ بِٱلْـَٔاخِرَةِ
[17:45]  ... those who do not believe in the Hereafter ...
Let us look at them consistently in the Quran, you find first, first of all Sura 16, verse 22.
16:22
Sura Al-Nahl
16:22 says,
[16:22]  Your god is one god. But those who do not believe in the Hereafter, their hearts are denying, and they are arrogant.
Okay,
[16:22]  Your god is one god. But those who do not believe in the Hereafter, ...
will set up other gods beside God.
This is what it means.
You see, you, you people are fortunate.
Most of you were born in a non-Muslim house.
And, and they, they will get double the reward.
This will be another Khutba.
You get twice as much as, as me,
the person who grew up in a Muslim house.
The Quran says that those who grew up in a non-Muslim house,
and they became Muslim,
and accepted the Quran as their book,
they get double the reward.
So, I grew up in a Muslim house.
My parents say,
if you are a good person,
you have to be a Muslim,
you must believe in God.
You must be a Muslim, you must believe in God, and so forth.
So, I grew up saying,
'Ana Muslim (I'm a Muslim), I believe in God.
'Ana Muslim (I'm a Muslim), I believe in God, you know.
Because my parents taught me so. But...
...Hereafter, we're gonna be resurrected, after death.
You know, they really don't believe it.
They just say it,
because their parents taught them to say that.
So, those who do not believe in the Hereafter, and their hearts are denying.
How do we distinguish?
This is the verse that, that I wanted to share next,
that those who do not believe in the Hereafter,
how will God show them on the Day of Judgment that they did not,
that their hearts were denying?
By this criterion here, when you tell them of the Quran alone, they run.
This is the criterion.
This is the sign
that will teach them, on the Day of Judgment,
that they were saying with their mouth, I'm a Muslim,
La Elaha Ella Allah,
but their hearts inside were denying,
and they didn't know it.
So, this is the sign.
Another verse about those who do not believe in in the Hereafter is in Sura 6, verse 112.
6:112 show us the Hadith and Sunnah test
where people do not believe God
when He says the Quran is complete and perfect.
(6:38) مَّا فَرَّطْنَا فِى ٱلْكِتَبِ مِن شَىْءٍ
(6:114) أَنزَلَ إِلَيْكُمُ ٱلْكِتَبَ مُفَصَّلًا
(6:115) تَمَّتْ كَلِمَتُ رَبِّكَ صِدْقًا وَعَدْلًا
They don't believe God
Because their, their, their hearts inside are denying.
So, when you read 112 it says,
[6:112]  Additionally, we have appointed for every prophet enemies—from among the human devils and jinn devils—who invent and narrate to each other fancy words, in order to deceive. Had your Lord willed, they would not have done it. You shall disregard them and their inventions.
We go on to 113.
[6:113]  This is God's way in order that the minds of those who do not really believe in the Hereafter ...
See? It's the same expression.
(6:113) لِتَصْغَىٓ إِلَيْهِ أَفْـِٔدَةُ ٱلَّذِينَ لَا يُؤْمِنُونَ بِالْأَخِرَةِ
Same expression.
Because their hearts inside are denying.
And we see that
لَا يُؤْمِنُونَ بِالْأَخِرَةِ
consistently,
those who do not believe in the Hereafter consistently.
They will, they will run away from the Quran alone.
They will be attracted to the fabrications
against the prophet, that they call Hadith and Sunnah.
And this will show them on the Day of Judgment
that their, their hearts were denying,
that they, they were not satisfied with the word of God alone.
39:45
39:45 is The Great Criterion* that tells you
if you or anyone you're speaking with, talking to
is really a believer or a false believer. It says,
[39:45]  When GOD ALONE is advocated, the hearts of those who do not believe in the Hereafter shrink with aversion. But when idols are mentioned besides Him, they rejoice.*
They become happy.
When you speak about Allah alone,
they don't like it.
(39:45) وَإِذَا ذُكِرَ ٱللَّهُ وَحْدَهُ ٱشْمَأَزَّتْ قُلُوبُ ٱلَّذِينَ لَا يُؤْمِنُونَ بِالْأَخِرَةِ
Again, those who do not believe in the Hereafter,
the same expression.
They don't like it.
You have to mention besides God, Mary or Jesus or Muhammad or Ali or somebody, something.
You cannot speak about Allah alone to them.
They will not be happy.
But when you mention someone else, they'll be happy.
So, this is a sign that they do not believe in the Hereafter
(39:45) ٱشْمَأَزَّتْ قُلُوبُ ٱلَّذِينَ لَا يُؤْمِنُونَ بِالْأَخِرَةِ وَإِذَا ذُكِرَ ٱلَّذِينَ مِن دُونِهِٓ إِذَا هُمْ يَسْتَبْشِرُونَ
That's the sign, the great criterion
for you, me, anyone you talk to.
And this is why I have it at the beginning of the translation.
Because it is the great criterion.
It tells you exactly if your heart is denying or not,
if you are a Muslim or you're deceiving yourself,
you tell yourself, I'm a Muslim, I'm a Muslim, when you're really not.
These are the signs.
Finally,
let's look up the same Sura 39, verse 65.
Prophet Muhammad is our example,
and his example is to uphold the Quran,
the whole Quran, nothing but the Quran.
And here is a statement direct us to the prophet. It says,
[39:65]  It has been revealed to you (Muhammad), and to those before you that if you ever fall into idol worship, all your works will be nullified, and you will be a loser.
After all the work he did,
after all the suffering he went through,
after being banished from his home town,
if he ever fell in idol worship,
all his works would have been nullified.
It doesn't matter what a nice guy you are.
It doesn't, it doesn't, it doesn't matter how nice you are, how honest and truthful
and beloved and benevolent and charitable,
it doesn't matter if you, if you idolize anyone or anything,
all your work is in vain.
Because we exist in this world
to worship Allah alone.
This is the whole idea.
Because Satan wanted to be a god with God.
So, God created us to show Satan, and to show the angels
that we will worship God without
putting anything besides Him.
If we put Muhammad next to Allah,
or Jesus next to Allah, or Mary next to Allah,
then we'll prove Satan's point.
We prove that God needs a partner,
God needs Muhammad in order to be worshipped,
or God needs Jesus to be worshipped,
or God needs Moses or Mary or something
to be worshipped.
We are here to prove that God can be worshipped alone,
without anything with Him.
This is the whole idea of the Quran.
And this is the, this is why it is the only unforgivable offense.
Another finally, I just remembered another verse
instead of 40.
Verse 10, we're gonna start at 10.
40:10
I'm gonna close with this I promise.
At the bottom of the page 321,
page 321 at the bottom,
it says, worship God alone.
It says,
[40:10]  Those who disbelieve will be told, ...
on the Day of Judgment
[40:10]  ... "God's abhorrence towards you is even greater than your abhorrence towards yourselves. Because you were invited to believe, but you chose to disbelieve."
11 says,
[40:11]  They will say, "Our Lord, you have given us two deaths,* and two lives; we now confess our sins. Is there any way out?"
that is out of Hell.
The answer in 12 says,
[40:12]  This is because when invited to worship GOD ALONE, you disbelieved, but when idols were mentioned besides Him, you believed. Alas, the judgment has been decreed by God; the Most Exalted, the Great.
So, just to give this subject, these verses, very important verses, justice, and we'll read them in Arabic again.
إِنَّ ٱلَّذِينَ كَفَرُوا يُنَادَوْنَ لَمَقْتُ ٱللَّهِ أَكْبَرُ مِن مَّقْتِكُمْ أَنفُسَكُمْ إِذْ تُدْعَوْنَ إِلَى ٱلْإِيمَنِ فَتَكْفُرُونَ (40:10)
قَالُوا رَبَّنَآ أَمَتَّنَا ٱثْنَتَيْنِ وَأَحْيَيْتَنَا ٱثْنَتَيْنِ فَٱعْتَرَفْنَا بِذُنُوبِنَا فَهَلْ إِلَى خُرُوجٍ مِّن سَبِيلٍ (40:11)
ذَلِكُم بِأَنَّهُٓ إِذَا دُعِىَ ٱللَّهُ وَحْدَهُ كَفَرْتُمْ وَإِن يُشْرَكْ بِهِ تُؤْمِنُوا فَٱلْحُكْمُ لِلَّهِ ٱلْعَلِىِّ ٱلْكَبِيرِ (40:12)
عبادالله
(16:90) إِنَّ ٱللَّهَ يَأْمُرُ بِٱلْعَدْلِ وَٱلْإِحْسَنِ وَإِيتَآئِ ذِى ٱلْقُرْبَى
(unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Aqem Al-Salat
A man: Allahu Akbar. Allahu Akbar. Ash-hadu Alla Elaha Ella Allah
Hayya Alal Salat
Hayya Alal Falah.
Allahu Akbar. Allahu Akbar.
A man: La Elaha Ella Allah
Dr. Khalifa: Now, they happily, they have happily paying for the (unintelligible)
A woman: Well, yeah, I mean, (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: But that's, that's a wrong concept of everyone's sins.
Dr. Khalifa: That's...
A man: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Let's listen to these questions and answer, maybe we'll, we'll, God wants us to benefit from them.
The, the concept that we are all sailors is we, we do go through stages,
where, where we do not follow
the commands exactly.
But you can be sinless.
I mean, hopefully, before you die, you're gonna reach a stage where you are, you are absolutely sinless.
You won't have any sins in the past.
Alhamdu Lillah, right now, you, you repented, you are sinless right now.
Now, it is in your hand to commit a sin or not, as of this moment.
Now, if you fall in sin by, by, due to ignorance, and then you repent, you know what to do.
But it is absolutely in your hand to follow the Quran exactly to the letter.
This makes. sense?
We, we do not have to be sinners.
It is not true that we are all sinners.
You can get rid of all your sins.
And you, and you, therefore, from that time on, you have a perfect life.
This is what God says.
You have a perfect life, absolutely no problems,
no traffic tickets, no headache, no stomachache, no sickness.
You're guaranteed, absolutely guaranteed, health, wealth, peace of mind, perfect happiness.
This is what God says in the Quran.
Sura 24, verse 55.
And you better believe what God promises there.
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah.
A man: Like, getting back to the point of how I'm trying that it did not harm you. It's very common belief in this.
A man: At least (unintelligible) that there are things like evil eyes and amulets and...
Dr. Khalifa: Right.
A man: Like, like, people can look at you in a certain way and cause you to be ill or something like this.
A man: This, this is, this is idol worship.
Dr. Khalifa: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Right.
If you are afraid of anything, if someone points a gun to your hand and you get scared,
you're on idol worship.
You shouldn't be.
I mean, I mean, I'm giving you an extreme.
Because that gun will not work unless it is in accordance with God's will.
And if it is God's will that you die in that moment, there is nothing anyone in the whole world can do about it.
Because the method and time of your death is already written down.
And you cannot die except with a personal decree from God, personal decree.
(3:145) وَمَا كَانَ لِنَفْسٍ أَن تَمُوتَ إِلَّا بِإِذْنِ ٱللَّهِ كِتَبًا مُّؤَجَّلًا
Written down. Decreed.
God must sign your death certificate.
Therefore, a person comes with a gun can do nothing to you.
Because they have to sign the certificate of your death from God Himself personally.
No one knows when you will die, no one.
This is what the Quran says at the end of Sura 31.
Not even the angels who guard you.
Not until the order comes from Allah Subhanahu Wa Ta'ala.
Dr. Khalifa: You had a question.
A man: Yes. You said earlier that they would receive a double reward
Dr. Khalifa: Right.
A man: for converting to Muslims.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
A man: And you stated before that everybody has the same test.
So, I don't, you know, that seems like a contradiction,
for them to get a double reward.
A man: They're passing the same test.
Dr. Khalifa: No. They have, they have additional hurdles that they have to, to cross.
Because their parents told them "Jesus is God. Jesus is son of God." The trinity.
This, this kind of things.
And they have to overcome this
to, besides, if God wants to be generous with them, there's nothing anyone can do.
So, this is what God says.
God says, that if you, if you grew up under non-Muslim circumstances and you come to Quran,
Dr. Khalifa: you will, you, you receive double the reward.
A man: So, their test is, is more difficult.
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah. Their test is more difficult.
A man: And everybody else (unintelligible)
Audience: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Maybe, it does. Maybe not. Yeah.
A man: Where does it say that?
Dr. Khalifa: This doesn't...
A man: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: The, the end, for example, the end of Sura 57.
A man: End of 57?
Dr. Khalifa: Yes. And there's also towards the end of Sura 5.
I will give a Khutba on this subject (unintelligible), IN SHAA ALLAH.
Congratulations.
Taghabal Allah (تقبل الله)
Dr. Khalifa: Congratulations.
Dean Mahmoud: Oh, it's there. (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Ok. We're gonna, I think, we're at 196.
A woman: What verse?
Dr. Khalifa: 196.
Dr. Khalifa: This is Christmas Eve and it seems like a lot of people are having family reunions.
A woman: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: They're watching...
Dr. Khalifa: Is there football on the (unintelligible)?
A woman: No.
A woman: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Dukes of Hazzard.
A woman: It was very hard (unintelligible).
A man: Merry Christmas from your house (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Page 21. Hajj pilgrimage.
Here is a commandment.
[2:196]  You shall complete the Hajj and 'Umrah observance for GOD. If you are prevented, then offer a sacrifice, and do not resume cutting your hair until your offering has reached its destination. ...
[2:196]  ... But if you are ill, or suffering some head injury (then you may cut your hair), and expiate by fasting, or giving a charity, or some other form of worship. ...
[2:196]  ... During the normal times of peace, if you break the state of sanctity between 'Umrah and Hajj, then expiate by offering a sacrifice. Those who cannot afford it may fast three days during Hajj and seven when they return home—thus completing ten— ...
[2:196]  ... provided they do not live at the Sacred Mosque (Masjid). You shall observe GOD, and know that GOD is strict in enforcing judgement.
Okay. All this sounds complicated.
But it has to do with the Hajj ritual.
When you go for Hajj, IN SHAA ALLAH, you,
you start out by 'Umrah.
There are two things you have to do,
the 'Umrah and then the Hajj.
Dr. Khalifa: 'Umrah, 'Umrah consists of putting on the, the un-
A woman: souls.
Dr. Khalifa: -sewn souls
(unintelligible)
But the women are exempted. They are wearing white dresses.
Then, you go around the Ka'abah seven times.
Then, you, you run between the knolls of Safa and Marwah, seven times.
And that completes your 'Umrah. Then, you go into the Hajj.
So, if you decide to break the state of Ihraam, state of sanctity,
between
'Umrah and Hajj, see,
as soon as you enter into that state of sanctity, you don't do any
vanity, you don't make up
your face, you don't cut your hair.
It's a,
it's a, it's another form of
making the body your slave.
You're telling your body, I'm not gonna beautify you and
and, and make you
look pretty or anything until
this Hajj is over, so people don't shave.
The men don't shave, you don't cut your hair.
you can shower or everything
and, but you don't wear clothes that distinguish
the rich from the poor.
You wear very simple clothes, as you see.
For the men, it's just a sheet.
So, in Hajj, they are people who are going,
you cannot tell who is rich and who is poor.
And they all look unshaven, and
they all look
unmade up
and all that. So, all the
practices in Islam
are geared towards being the boss over your body.
Salat, the fasting, Hajj,
the Zakat charity.
So, let me go through this sentence by sentence now.
[2:196]  You shall complete the Hajj and 'Umrah observance for GOD. ...
So, this is something you have to do.
as soon as, whenever you can.
You plan on it
and when you can, God will make you able to, IN SHAA ALLAH, you go and do it.
Of course, the first person to announce Hajj was Abraham.
And this is,
let's look up Sura 22,
I think it is verse 27.
This is 22...